

#### Personal

Name Kaloyan Dzhongov

Address

5138 Polikraiste, Veliko Tarnovo

**Phone number** 0888033498

Email

kaloyan.dzhongov@gmail.com

**Nationality** Bulgarian

#### **Interests**

Sport, Theater, Programming

#### Characteristics

Responsible

Accurate

Loyal

Communicative

# **Kaloyan Dzhongov**

I have years of experience as a QA and Test Automator. I have worked with many tools and technologies related to software testing. I have always wanted to learn new things and have experience in Java, PHP, and JavaScript. I have an experience as a backend developer. I am responsible, work well with a team and have always been loyal to my employers.

### Work experience

#### **Automation tester**

Apr 2020 - Dec 2023

Ucha se, Varna

**Ucha.se** is the most popular educational platform in Bulgaria. The company also develops educational platforms in countries such as Romania, Spain and Italy.

**Role description:** Design and build a test environment from scratch Writing automated tests on Codeception ( PHP- testing framework ) and Appium.

#### System Analyzer and Quality Enginrer

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

Sirma Group, Varna

**Project: Temenos Policy Editor:** A file generation tool that sets the rights of employees of a banking institution

**Role description:** Writing System Specifications as User Stories, Writing test plan and executing Functional tests.

#### **Functional and Automation tester**

Apr 2016 - Aug 2019

Ruse, Varna

**Project:** Sirma Enterprise System:Company platform that is the basis for modeling a variety of enterprising products.

**Role description:** Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios, Automation testing. Development of test plan Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents, new builds testing, and writing definitions.

#### Quality Assurance

Aug 2014 - Mar 2016

Sirma Group, Ruse

**Project:** LEK. Project for developing of application for The National Council for Prices and Reimbursement of Medicinal Products

**Role description:** Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Development of test plan. Executing functional tests. Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents.

#### Functional and automation tester

Sep 2013 - Aug 2014

Sirma ITT, Ruse

**Project: Conservation Space.** Project for development of an application for NGA and its partners that addresses a core need of the conservation community for a shared solution to the problem of documentation, conservation, and cultural object management.

**Role description:** Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Development of Multi-platform test plan. Executing of Multi-platform tests. Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents builds testing. Defining, implementing and running automation test scripts

#### **Functional and Automation tester**

Jul 2012 - Sep 2013

Sirma ITT, Ruse

**Project:** Project for "Development of electronic administrative services", N: K10-31-1/7.9.2010 **Role description:** Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Executing conformance tests and Scenarios. Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents and new build testing. Defining, implementing, and running automation test scripts.

Java developer

Jul 2011 - Jun 2012

Sirma ITT, Ruse

Project: Wiki Migration: Internal Project for migration of data from one wiki tool to Confluence

**Role description:** Development of migration tool.

#### Functional and automation test engineer

Sirma ITT, Ruse

**Project:** Excise Management System for Bulgarian Customs Agency, (EMS2.1)

**Role description**: Writing and executing Functional, Integration, and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Reporting and verification bugs. Technical specification reviews. Writing automated tests. Developing a module for handling automated tests

#### **Quality Assurance**

Jul 2008 - Dec 2009

Mar 2010 - Jan 2011

Sirma ITT, Ruse

Project: Export Control System, Phase 2 (ECS2)

**Role description**: Functional manual testing. Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Executing conformance tests and Scenarios. Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents. Defining, implementing, and running automation test scripts.

#### **Quality Assurance**

Mar 2008 - Jul 2009

Sirma ITT, Ruse

**Project:** EMS1.E - Enhancements to the Bulgarian Excise Management System (EMS1.1): National Domain **Role:** Testing, Writing test documentation.

#### **Quality Assurance**

Feb 2007 - Mar 2008

Sirma ITT, Ruse

**Project:** PHARE EuropeAid/121988/D/SV/BG, BG 2004/016-711.10.05.01.11: Computerization of the Bulgarian Customs Administration Export procedures in line with the EU standards, Component 1: Development of Export Control System

**Role description**: Functional manual testing. Writing and executing Functional and UI Test Cases and Test Scenarios. Executing conformance tests and Scenarios. Reporting and verifying bugs. Preparation of test documents. Defining, implementing, and running automation test scripts.

#### Backend developer

Sep 2006 - Feb 2007

ITT Ltd., Ruse

Automated CV Generator Technologies: Java, EJB 2.1

Tools: Eclipse 3.1.2, IBM Rational Software Architect 6.0

Backend: Informix 10

Role description: Backend developer.

Application Server: WebSphere Application Server

## Skills

## **Education and Qualifications**

Master degree in Software Engineering	Sep 2009 - Sep 2011
Ruse University "Angel Kanchev", Ruse	
Bachelor degree in Computer Systems and Technologies  Ruse University "Angel Kanchev", Ruse	Sep 2004 - May 2008
Secondary School Diploma in Computer Systems and Technologies  Professional School "M. V. Lomonosov", Gorna Oryahovica	Sep 1999 - May 2004